

ABDUL WAJITH

DATA SCIENTIST

I have more than one year of experience in turning data into business solutions, looking forward to step into new career which provide a learning environment and be a better platform to apply my skills and enhance my knowledge.



Puttalam, Sri Lanka.



+9471 <u>959 38</u>29



azeeswajid@outlook.com







EDUCATION

Bachelor of business science (Hons) specialized in business analytics.

UNIVERSITY OF MORATUWA | SEP 2017 - MAR 2022

SKILLS

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Leadership & Teamwork
- Effective communications
- Willingness to learn & Creative thinking
- Analytical thinking & Problem solving

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming (Python & R)
- Database (SQL, NoSQL & elasticsearch)
- Visualization (Power BI, Tableau, Data Studio)
- · IT skills (MS Offices, Advanced excel)
- Data mining (WEKA)
- Web development (react js, Flask)

TOOLS & TECHNIQUE

- Machine Learning (Sk-learn, TF, Pytorch)
- NLP & OCR Tools & OpenCV Image Processing
- Web Scraping (selenium & Beautiful Soup)
- Model Deployment (Heroku, AWS, linux)
- Version control (github, tfs)
- Big Data (Hadoop)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Hand written digit recognition
- Spam email detection & Stock price prediction
- · Personality system
- Breast cancer & Kidney disease detection
- Movie recommender
- Loan approval prediction

CERTIFICATION

- Research paper publication certificate in 3rd South Asia conference on interdisciplinary research 2021
- 10+ Udemy course completion certificate in ML, DL, SQL, BI and R related projects

WORK EXPERIENCE

Deep Data Insights - Associate Data Scientist

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

- Researched & create BERT model and flask API for Psychology Risk prediction for players and coaches (FITINSIGHTS).
- Optimization, maintain, fixing the bugs, and create new flask APIs, version control & deploy, the Master index record match & deduplication with elastic search.
- Researched & Built documents AI Model (keyword search, Q & A and Tabular) using GPT-3 and haystack with elastic search and fully functioned flask APIs.
- Researched and improved psychology natural language chatbot using rasa

Hameedia groups - Business Analyst intern

DEC 2021 - MAR 2022

- Data preprocessed, ETL processed the data, wrote DAX functions & analyzed sales efficiency & contribution, business efficiency of inventory, prepared monthly rolling plans, sales forecasting, visualized business performance and identified possibilities for improvements using Power BI and excel.
- Identified difficulties, estimate KPIs and identified product aging, distressed stock, identified growth rate as well as described business implications and reporting the stakeholders & top management.

FINAL YEAR PROJECT

Real estate housing information extracting using OCR & NLP from E-news to develop database.

- Collected the images from 6 various e-news domains using selenium & preprocessed, filtered image noises using openCV & used tesseract engine to extract the textual data.
- Text preprocessed such as decoding data, removal of stop-words, lemmatization, stemming, standardizing words and missing value imputation using NLP.
- Extracted information using ruled-base approach & Custom NER ML model techniques to database.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Tamil
- Sinhala

REFERRAL

Dr. I. Mahakalanda

Head - Department of Decision Sciences.

- +9411 265 0301.
- indram@uom.lk.

Mr. Simaque Nayeem

Exports and Logistics Manager - Hameedia Groups.

- +9477 306 0182.
- mld@hameedia.lk.